Earth.
土强
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！
Fire.
火烈
Air.
气和
Water.
水善
Only the Avatar can master all four elements
只有神通能掌握所有四种元素
and bring balance to the world.
并为世界带来平衡
降世神通：科拉传奇
Unalaq has forced Korra into opening the northern portal
吴纳克强迫科拉打开北极大门
and trapped Jinora in the spirit world.
把吉诺拉困在灵界
Back in Republic City,
回到共和城
everybody loves Varrick's Nuktuk movers.
所有人都喜欢瓦里克的纳塔克系列电影
Everybody, that is, except Mako,
所有人，除了信
whose pursuit of Varrick has landed him in the slammer.
对瓦里克进行追查，结果他被整进监狱
And in the Southern water tribe,
南极水族这边
Unalaq's army is nearing victory in the civil war.
吴纳克的军队在内战中就要胜利了
But Tonraq isn't about to give up without a fight.
但托纳克非战不屈
第二册：神灵篇
第十一集：繁星之夜
Dad's back!
爸爸回来了
Where's Jinora?
吉诺拉呢？
No!
不
Her spirit is trapped in the spirit world,
她的魂魄被困在灵界了
but she's going to be all right.
但她不会有事的
How could this happen?
怎么会这样
It was all my fault.
全是我的错
I should have never let Jinora enter the spirit world without me.
我不该让吉诺拉没有我陪伴就进入灵界
I couldn't protect her.
我没能保护她
I'm so sorry, Pema.
我很抱歉，姵玛
I tried to save her, but Unalaq tricked me.
我想救她，可是吴纳克骗了我
Don't worry, honey,
别担心，亲爱的
I'm not going to stop until our little girl is back safe with us.
在我们的女儿回来前，我不会停手的
You've got a visitor.
有人探监
Hey, Mako.
嗨，信
Hey.
嗨
What's with the fancy duds?
干嘛穿那么花
I'm on my way to the big finale for <i>Nuktuk: Hero of the South.</i>
我准备去《纳塔克：南方英雄》的终场呢
Yeah, everyone's gonna be there,
大家都会去的
except for, you know,
只是缺了……嗯
you...
缺你
Because you're in jail and stuff.
因为你在蹲监狱什么的
Thanks for the reminder.
谢谢提醒
Hey, I brought you something.
等等，我有东西给你
I thought this would brighten up your new place.
说不定能让你好好装扮一下这
Read the inscription.
你读读
"Dear Mako, Nuktuk says, 'keep smiling.'"
亲爱的信，纳塔克说，要保持笑容
did you come by just to give me a poster?
你来这里就为了给我张海报？
No,
不
I came by to give you my sincere, heartfelt words of encouragement.
我来是给你我最真挚的，发自内心的祝福
I know our lives have been moving in two different directions,
我知道我们的生活踏上了两条不同的道路
but I want you to know that I will always be there for you.
但我要你知道我永远会支持你
We are brothers, after all,
毕竟，我们是兄弟
even if one of us is a member of high society and the other one is a criminal.
哪怕我们一个入了上流社会，另一个成了罪犯，也一样
I am not a criminal!
我不是罪犯
Of course I know that,
我当然知道你不是
but you do kinda look like one,
可是你长得确实像罪犯
'cause you're in a jail, and that's where criminals live.
因为你在监狱里，监狱又是关罪犯的
I was set up!
我是被算计了
Varrick knew I had figured out he was hiring gangsters to pose as northern soldiers
瓦里克知道我看破了他雇佣黑社会装成北方士兵
to get Republic City to join the war.
想让共和城加入战争的技俩
That's why he had me arrested.
所以他把我抓起来了
Ah, I see what you're doing. You're going for the insanity defense.
啊，我明白你在做什么了，你“精神失常”了
Smart.
真有你的
No!
不！
I'm trying to tell you that Varrick isn't what he seems.
我是要告诉你瓦里克肚里没安好心
Where's Asami? She'll listen to me.
麻美呢，她会听懂我的
I asked her to come, but she said it was too hard for her.
我让她也同来，可是她说，这对她太难受了
You being in jail like this
你这样蹲监狱
reminds her of her dad.
让她想起她爸爸
Okay, gotta run,
好吧，我得走了
but I'll be back tomorrow.
但明天我会还来的
And I am gonna get you the best attorney fame and fortune can buy.
我要给你请来我请得起的最好的律师
Bolin, wait.
波林，等一下
If my theory about Varrick is right,
如果我对瓦里克的推测没错
something might go down tonight at your premiere.
今天你的终场上肯定会出大事
Promise me you'll keep your eyes peeled.
你得保证，得多留个心眼
Yeah, okay, big brother.
啊，行行行，老大哥
I promise.
我保证
That insanity defense is definitely gonna work.
“精神失常”这招绝对奏效
Should we wait another day?
我们要再等一天么
Korra still might come with reinforcements.
科拉仍然有可能带着援兵回来的
We can't wait any longer.
我们不能再等了
It's time we take back what is ours!
现在我们得夺回属于我们的东西了
It's time to take back our city!
现在是夺回我们城市的时刻了
Yeah
然也
Say "Nuktuk."
说纳塔克
There they are, folks,
各位，他们来了
the sweethearts of the big screen,
荧幕上的小俩口
and Republic City's most famous couple,
也是共和城最出名的一对
Bolin and ginger.
波林和小姜
Let me get a picture.
让我拍张照
Wow, that was fun.
喔，真有意思
And did you hear what Shiro said?
你听到四郎说什么了没
We're Republic City's most famous couple.
我们是共和城最出名的一对
Bolin, you're a doll,
波林，你这个笨蛋
but you're as dumb as the rocks you bend.
你脑子笨得像你御的石头一样
We are not a couple.
我们可不是一对
That's not what Shiro said.
四郎可没那么说啊
Stop stuffing your moustaches with varri-cakes and get to your post!
你别再往嘴里填蛋糕了，快去站岗
You got it, boss.
遵命，长官
You two are the pinnacle of refinement.
你们俩可真是人上人啊
This star-studded event just keeps getting star-studdier, folks.
各位，群星荟萃的大会又有明星加入了
President Raiko and the first lady, Buttercup Raiko, just arrived.
雷鼓总统和第一夫人雷鼓毛茛刚刚驾临
And they're being greeted by entrepreneur extraordinaire,
迎接他们的是杰出企业家
Varrick.
瓦里克
There they are, my two most honored guests.
您二位贵宾终于来了
What do you think?
怎么样
No expense has been spared.
预算我一点都没省
I brought in the finest entertainers from Ba Sing Se
我请来了永固城最好的演员
and the best food from around the world.
弄来了各地最好的食物
Heck, I even had this red carpet imported from the fire nation.
哈，我还从火烈国进口了这条红地毯
They make the best red stuff over there.
他们造的红色东西那是顶呱呱
In fact... all right, picture time!
其实吧…好，来合个影
Varrick, you didn't have to do all this for us.
瓦里克，你不需要为我们做这些的
I wanted to.
我想要嘛
Mr. President, I took one look at your wife,
总统大人，一见到您的夫人
and I knew that you were a man of exquisite taste.
我就知道您是一位品味上流的人
And that's why I know you're gonna love this mover!
所以我知道您肯定会喜欢这电影
Varrick, I know what you're doing,
瓦里克，我知道你在做什么
and I doubt your propaganda is going to change my mind about going to war with the northern water tribe.
我看你的宣传作秀是不会打动我和北方水族部落开战的
Oh, I think you'll be surprised how persuasive I can be.
哦，我的说服力会让您刮目相看的
Thank you all for coming to the finale of <i>Nuktuk: Hero of the South.</i>
谢谢各位来观看《纳塔克：南方英雄》的终场
You know, when I first started this project,
其实，在我刚开始这个企划的时候
there were a lot of naysayers out there.
反对者相当的多
"You can't make pictures move," they said.
他们说“你怎么可能让画面动起来”
"You can't take some knucklehead earthbender and make him a star," they said.
他们说“你不可能让那个笨蛋御土师成为明星”
"You can't teach a polar bear dog to speak," they said.
他们还说“你不可能让极熊狗会说话，”
Well, they're wrong.
现在，他们都错了
Thanks to the magic of the movers,
多亏这电影的神奇
our furry friends have found their voices.
我们毛茸茸的小家伙也会说话了
And you'll be shocked to hear what they have to say.
他们要说的话，会让你们大吃一惊
They speak of the injustice that's happening in the Southern water tribe right now.
他们所说的是，在南方水族部落正发生的不义之举
My hope is that their words
我希望他们的话
and this epic mover
还有这部史诗般的电影
will inspire a real-life hero to rise up and help.
会让现实中诞生一位英雄揭竿而起，拔刀相助
Thank you again.
谢谢各位
Enjoy the show.
请看电影吧
When last we left our hero, be was captured by the evil Unalaq's dastardly pet bird.
上回我们说到
我们的英雄被邪恶的吴纳克那卑鄙的宠物鸟抓走了
Amazingly, with the power of his whistling, Nuktuk escaped...
但不可思议的是，凭着口哨功夫，纳塔克逃走了
And decided to seek out counsel.
然后决心去寻求议会的帮助
Thank you, wise sage.
谢谢你，贤者
I will travel to Republic City and seek help.
我这就去共和城请求救兵
Have a seat.
请坐
I'm just working on a cure for the common cold.
我正在研究流感的解药呢
No longer will my citizens suffer from the sniffles.
我的市民们不久再也不会受鼻塞之苦了
Mr. President, there's something more important than the sniffles right now.
总统先生，现在有件事比鼻塞更重要
I need your help to stop the evil Unalaq.
我需要您帮忙阻止邪恶的吴纳克
Did you say "help"?
你说帮忙？
If there is one thing I love doing, it's helping people.
如果有什么东西我喜欢做，那肯定就是帮人一把了
The seal line seemed a bit far-fetched,
这台词虽然有点牵强
不过这位总统的形象还真像回事
but the portrayal of this president is right on the money.
I think this is your best mover yet.
我感觉这是你目前最棒的电影
I just wish Mako was here to see it.
我真希望信也能来看
I like to eat the top off the varri-cake first.
我喜欢先吃瓦里牌蛋糕的上面
I just try to shove the whole thing in my mouth at once.
我嘛就一口吞下去
I love our job.
我爱我们的工作
Northern water tribe automatons!
北方水族机器人
Nooo!
不要
Nuktuk cannot stop Unalaq.
纳塔克无法阻止吴纳克
Must destroy Nuktuk.
必须消灭纳塔克
Looks like you forgot that water and automatons don't mix.
看来你好像忘了机器人不能碰到水
Oh, no, circuits not working.
不！电路无法工作了
We did it!
我们做到了
But wait.
不过等等
Where's Juji?
朱吉在哪里
Nukno!
不要
You can't die, Juji.
朱吉你不能死
Not on my watch.
我不要亲眼看着你死啊
It's okay, Nuktuk.
没事的，纳塔克
At least I got to be...
至少，我曾做过
Your friend.
你的朋友
Juji!
朱吉
Are you okay?
你还好吧？
It seems like this mover is really getting to you.
看起来你好像真的入戏了
You do know Juji's not really dead?
你应该知道朱吉并没有真正死了吧
Of course I know. Juji's fine.
我当然知道他还好
He comes back to life in the end when the doomsday device shifts the polarity of the earth.
当吴纳克的末日武装倒转地球磁极的时候，他复活了
Oops. Spoiler.
哦，剧透了
Sorry.
不好意思
Then what's wrong?
那你怎么了
I guess I just miss my friends.
可能我是想念我的朋友了
Everything is going so well for me,
我现在一帆风顺
but it feels empty without everyone around.
然而没有大家的陪伴，我心里空落落的
Korra's gone, Mako's in jail, you're doing...
科拉走了，马克入狱了，而你
Business lady stuff.
现在忙于商务
Team Avatar's fallen apart.
神通小队已经支离破碎
I know.
我明白
Things have changed so much since we first met.
自我们相遇以来，世事变化巨大
Why don't you come back in and fish watching the mover with me?
你怎么不进来和我一起看完这电影
You go ahead.
你去吧
I need another minute.
我自己再待会儿
That's weird.
这有点不对劲
They're after the president!
他们是冲着总统来的
You're too late, Nuktuk.
你来得太迟了纳塔克
Soon, my doomsday device will shoot this block of ice into the earth's core,
很快，我的末日武装将会把这块寒冰射入地核
freezing the entire planet.
冰冻整个世界
And I will be the ruler of ice earth!
而我，将会成为冰雪世界的主宰
I don't think so.
我不这样认为
Mr. President, get back!
总统先生，退到后面
I'm here to help.
我是来救你的
Looks like there's nowhere to go.
看来你们已经无路可走了
Secure the president and call for backup immediately!
立刻联系后援，保护总统
Nuktuk, Bolin, look out!
波林（纳塔克）小心
This is unbelievable!
这简直难以置信
Bolin is bending two full stacks of earth discs at once,
波林同时御着两叠全部的土盘
which would normally be illegal.
这在平时是犯规的
But then again, he's fighting three waterbenders,
不过，他正在独力和三名水宗对抗
so all rules are out the window.
所以还管他什么规定
Tell me who sent you!
告诉我是谁指使你的
It was Varrick. Please don't hurt me, Nuktuk!
是瓦里克，请不要伤害我，纳塔克
I think this is our cue to exit.
我想我们该跑路了
Where do you think you're going?
你以为你还去得了哪里
It's a knockout!
击倒
They're falling back.
他们撤退了
Varrick's plan was to kidnap you and blame it on the north.
瓦里克的计划是绑架你然后把帐算到北极水族头上
Then Republic City would have no choice but to join the war on the side of the South.
那样，共和城将别无选择，只能与南方并肩作战
I can't believe Varrick would do something like this,
我不敢相信瓦里克居然能做出这种事
and no one saw it coming.
而且竟然没人识破他的诡计
Actually, someone did.
事实上有人识破了
Remember Mako?
还记得信吗
You've got a great officer on your hands.
你有一名很好的警员
He's one of the best.
他是最棒的警官之一
I can't believe my boyfriend is a real-life hero.
我不敢相信，我的男友在现实生活中竟然也是英雄
Boyfriend?
男友？
Wait, stop. I thought you said we <i>weren't</i> a couple.
等等，我想你说过我们不是一对
You really are as dumb as those rocks. Of course we're a couple.
你真是和那堆石头一样木讷，我们当然是一对
Bolin, you saved the president.
波林你救下了总统
And you proved Mako was right all along.
而且你证明了信的清白
We have to go tell him what happened.
我们得告诉他事情经过
Yeah.
是啊
Oh, you meant right now.
噢，你是说现在吗？
President Raiko...
雷鼓总统
Avatar Korra, what's wrong?
神通科拉，怎么了
Sir, I know I've asked for your help before,
先生，我知道我之前就已经向您提过请求
but things have changed.
但是现在情况不同
Unalaq doesn't just want to take over the South anymore.
吴纳克不止想要占领水族
He wants to destroy the whole world.
他还想要毁灭整个世界
Unalaq is gonna destroy the world?
吴纳克要毁灭世界？
He really does have a doomsday device?
他真有末日武装吗？
He's trying to release a powerful dark spirit during harmonic convergence, which is only a few days away.
他准备在几天后的谐波汇聚时，释放一只强大的黑暗神灵
If he succeeds,
如果他成功了
the world as we know it is over.
我们现在认识的世界就完了
Sir, we desperately need your help.
先生，我们急需你的帮助
I'm sorry, Korra, but my answer is still no.
很抱歉科拉，我依旧只能说不
There are lives on the line! And my daughter is one of them.
我的女儿和很多其他人已经命悬一线了
Raiko, you must reconsider.
雷鼓，我必须请你三思
I'm aware that lives are on the line,
我知道很多人有性命危险
and that's precisely why my troops are staying here.
这也是我的部队一直得留在这里的原因
If the world is going to be thrown into chaos, like you claim,
如果这个世界如你们所说将要陷入混乱
I need to protect my citizens.
我需要保护我的人民
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
Sir. Nuktuk needs your help.
先生，纳塔克需要你的帮助
I know you love helping people.
我知道你喜欢帮助别人
Son, I appreciate you saving my life, and I'm a big fan of your work,
孩子，我感谢你救了我的命，你的作品也很喜欢
but my decision is final.
但是我意已决
I never should have saved that guy.
我真不该救他
If you guys need help, I'm here for you.
你们需要帮助的话，有我在
Yeah, me too.
嗯，我也在
Thank you. It's so good to see you guys again.
谢谢，能再次与你们相聚真好
Wait, where's Mako?
等等，信呢
So how was the big premiere?
你那隆重的首秀怎么样了
I saved the president! In real life!
我救了总统！可不是在戏里哦
Wait, what?
等等，什么？
You were right about Varrick. He tried to kidnap Raiko!
你对瓦里克的看法是正确的，他想绑架雷鼓
I knew it.
我就知道
But it didn't work, because of you. And because of me.
但是这个计划失败了，因为有我们两个
Let's just say we both did good. Beifong says you're free to go.
好吧，就算我们都有功劳，北方警长说你可以走了
Sorry for ever doubting you, Mako.
信，当时怀疑你真抱歉
Don't worry about it, bro.
兄弟，别放在心上
Nice job, Mako. You're going to make a great Detective.
信，干得好，你会成为名侦探的
But, chief, there aren't any Detective openings right now.
但是警长，现在警探部门没有空缺啊
Actually, we have two openings.
其实我刚刚找到了两个空缺
Mako, I missed you so much.
信，我太想念你了
Oh, yeah, did I forget to tell you? Korra's back.
哦，我是不是忘记告诉你了，科拉回来了
Korra,
科拉
hey, I missed you too.
嘿，我也想你
So you're not still mad at me?
你不生我气了？
Why would I be mad?
我为什么要生气呢？
We had that fight before you left, remember?
你走之前我们吵了一架，还记得吗？
No, not really.
不，记不得了
I got attacked by a dark spirit,
我之后被一个黑暗神灵袭击了
and I lost my memory for a little while.
那段时间失忆了
Maybe it hasn't all come back yet.
也许还没完全恢复吧
Was it a bad fight?
那次争吵得厉害吗？
No. No, it... it wasn't that bad.
不，不，没那么糟糕
Korra, we don't have much time.
科拉，我们没有多少时间了
We need to figure out how to deal with Unalaq.
我们得想出对付吴纳克的办法
I think I know just the man to talk to.
我想我应该知道现在需要谁了
Guys, hey!
伙计们，嘿
What do you think? Varrick industries built this prison,
怎么样，瓦里克重工建造了这个监狱
and I had this cell made special.
然后我给这个牢房做了些特殊的打点
I had a feeling I'd end up here one day.
看来我今儿得在这里过上一天了
Zhu Li, come on! We got guests.
朱莉，快来，我们有客人了
Whip up a pot of that green tea I love.
快沏上一壶我最喜欢的那种绿茶
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Zhu Li's in prison with you?
朱莉和你一起坐牢么
Of course. I don't go anywhere without my assistant. Do you?
当然，我去哪都要带上我的助理，你们还不知道么
We're not interested in your tea, and this isn't a friendly visit.
我们对你的茶没兴趣，而且我们不是来探监的
Don't tell me you guys are still mad about everything that happened.
别告诉我你们还在为那些发生过的事生气
I did some good things too.
我也干过好事
Korra, who warned you about Unalaq?
科拉，是谁警告你吴纳克没安好心的？
I did.
是我
Bolin, who got you into the movers?
波林，是谁让你演那部电影的？
I did.
是我
Asami, who saved your company?
麻美，是谁拯救了你的公司？
I did.
是我
Mako, who got you thrown in jail?
诚哥，是谁让你蹲了监狱？
I did.
还是我
Oh, yeah, I guess that was a bad thing.
哦，对了，好像那不是件好事
You stole everything from me, and you tried to kidnap the president.
你夺走了我的一切，而且你试图绑架总统
Those are pretty bad too.
那些也是坏事
I wasn't going to hurt him.
我不想伤害他
I just needed to start a war.
我只想引发战争
Well, a bigger war.
一场大战
Well, we're gonna end it. Where's all the stuff you stole from Asami?
我们要结束这场战争，你从麻美那都偷了些什么
The future industries stuff? It's on my battleship.
未来实业的那些？都在我的战列舰上
You have a battleship?
你居然有战列舰
Of course I do!
当然有
I bought the first one they made,
他们造的第一艘我就买下来了
named her the <i>Zhu Li.</i>
她的舰名是：朱莉
You named your battleship after your assistant?
你用你的助理命名战列舰么
Yep. They're both cold, heartless war machines.
对，她们都是冷血无情的战争机器
Your tea, sir.
先生，茶好了
Look, I am truly sorry for the mess I caused.
这么说吧，我对我造成的烂摊子表示抱歉
Let me make it up to you.
我就来补偿你们吧
Take <i>Zhu Li.</i>
朱莉归你们了
My battleship, it's yours, and everything on it.
是朱莉号，上面所有的东西也是
It's not the fleet we were looking for, but it's the next best thing.
虽然不是我们想要的船，但这其实也不错
All right! Team Avatar is back in business!
好！神通小组重新启航了
It's okay.
没事的
We're gonna stop Unalaq and get Jinora back.
我们一定能阻止吴纳克并救回吉诺拉的
I hope my dad's all right.
我希望我父亲没事
I'm sure he's fine.
我肯定他没事
Get the men and fall back.
带上他们撤退
What about you?
你自己怎么办
I'm going to end this right now.
我现在就来解决这一切
Go!
去吧！
Hello, Tonraq.
你好啊托纳克
Looking for me?
是来找我的吗？
Brother, I'm too strong for you.
哥哥，我比你强太多了
You're no brother of mine.
你根本不是我弟弟
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我
You had me banished.
是你把我流放走了
Yes, I did.
没错，就是我
Stop!
住手
He's mine.
他是我的猎物
You are not the true chief.
你不是真正的族长
I am.
我是
And you will bow to me.
你还不赶紧给我鞠躬
Now that I've defeated you,
现在我打倒你了
your daughter is next.
下一个就轮到你女儿了
降世神通贴吧&Brony United
片源：Ult-Kimi 英文：DracoRunan 翻译：TNBi，蓝色的夏天，Blackdragon
校对：水族神通 调轴：水族神通
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！